I took a cell phone
استقبلت مكالمة هاتفية
and accidentally made myself famous.
وبالصدفة جعلت من نفسي مشهور.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I was just talking about the things that I cared about,
كنت أتحدث فقط عن الأمور التي اهتممت بها،
but with the click of a button
لكن بضغطة زر
and an incendiary viral video
وبفيديو فيروسى
I propelled myself into overnight stardom.
دفعت نفسي إلى النجومية بين ليلة وضحاها.
When I say overnight,
عندما أقول بين ليلة وضحاها،
I mean I literally woke up the next morning
أعني اني حرفيًا أفقت الصباح التالي
with so many notifications on my phone,
مع العديد من التنبيهات على هاتفي،
I thought I slept through a national tragedy.
اعتقدت بأنني نمت خلال حدوث مأساة وطنية.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
It was the craziest thing, guys,
كان ذلك من أكثر الأشياء جنوناً،
but when it came to my influence and my exposure,
ولكن عندما تعلق الأمر بظهوري وتأثيري،
I literally took a quantum leap.
كان فعلاً نقلة نوعية.
So I made more videos
لذا صوّرت افلام أكثر
and the subject matter of my videos
وموضوعات للفيديوهات الخاصة بى
was often the most divisive subject in American life,
غالباً ماكان عن سبب الخلاف في الحياة
but it was the way that I articulated race
ولكن الطريقة التي أوضحت بها المسالة
that made me somewhat of a digital lightning rod.
جعلتنى شيئا كالبرق
See, being a survivor myself of police brutality
كماترون، كونني ناجٍ من وحشية الشرطة
and having lost a childhood friend,
وخسرت صديق الطفولة،
Alonzo Ashley,
الونزو آشلي،
at the hands of the police,
بيد الشرطة،
I had a little something to say about the topic.
لدي شيء صغير لأقوله حول هذا الموضوع
You see, this was at the height of the Black Lives Matter furor
كما ترون، ، كان هذا في ذروة مسأله الأحتجاجات على حياة السمر
and people seemed to be turning to me to articulate their viewpoints,
وبدا الناس يتوجهون لي لأعبرعن وجهات نظرهم،
and honestly, it was sort of overwhelming.
وبصدق، كان الأمر أكبر من قدرتي.
You see, the internet has this interesting quality.
وكما تعلمون،الانترنت لديه هذه الميزة الشيقة.
In one way, it totally brought the world together,
بطريقة ما، يقرّب العالم ببعضه البعض
and I remember being a kid
وأتذكر عندما كنت طفلًا
and all of this utopian propaganda was being dumped on us
وكل هذه الدعايات المثالية التي تُرمى علينا
about how the World Wide Web
كيف أن الشبكات العنكبوتية
was going to span the reaches of people across the globe.
سوف تمتد لتصل للناس في كل أنحاء العالم.
But as it turns out, people are people.
ولكن اتضح بأن الناس، كما هم
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And this magical superhighway
وهذا الطريق السريع السحري
also took the demons of our nature
أخذ طبيعتنا الشيطانية
and gave them Ferraris.
وأعطاهم ٍسيارات فيراري
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
You see, technology, y'all, is a lot like money.
كما ترون، التكنولوجيا، تشبه المال.
It just brings out what's already inside you and amplifies it.
إنها فقط تظهر ما هو موجود بداخلك أساساً وتضخمه.
And so I soon became familiar with the phenomenon of the internet troll.
وبعدها أصبحت مطلع علي ظاهرة أقزام الانترنت
These guys seem to live beneath the bridges
هؤلاء الأشخاص يبدو أنهم يعيشون تحت الجسور
of said superhighway --
التي يقال عندها طرق سريعة خارقة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And they also missed the memo about the enlightenment of the internet age.
ولم يحضروا المذكرة التي تحدثت عن عصر تنوير الإنترنت.
I remember being called
أتذكر حينما أُطلق علي
highly colorful racial slurs
عنصري للغاية وذو بشرة ملونة
by those who use the anonymity of the internet
بواسطة هؤلاء الذين يستخدمون هويات مستعارة على الإنترنت
as a Klan hood.
كجماعة كلان.
And some of them were pretty creative, actually,
وبعضًا منهم كان مبدع حقاً،
but others were pretty wounding,
ولكن الآخرون كانوا جارحون للغاية،
especially navigating the post-traumatic world
خصوصًا عند التنقل في عالم مابعد الصدمه
of a police brutality survivor
لناجٍ من وحشية الشرطة
in the height of Black Lives Matter,
في ذروة الإحتجاجات على حياة السمر،
with all of these people being killed on my timeline.
مع كل هؤلاء الأشخاص الذين يُقتلون في صفحتي الشخصيه.
To these trolls, I wasn't a human.
لهؤلاء المتصيدون، لم أكن انسان.
I was an idea, an object,
كنت فكرة، غرض،
a caricature.
كاريكاتير.
Did I mention that this race stuff can be kind of divisive?
هل ذكرت ان هذه الأمورالعرقية من الممكن ان تكون مُفرقة؟
You see, I'm an innately curious person
كما تعلمون، انا شخص فضولي بالفطرة
and as I drew my sword to engage in epic battles in the comment section --
كما قمت باستلال سيفي للمشاركة في هذه المعارك الملحمية في خانة التعليقات.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I also began to notice
بدأت ألاحظ ايضًا
that a few of my trolls actually had brains,
بأن المتصيدين في الواقع يملكون عقول
which made me even more curious and what to understand them even further.
الأمر الذي جعلني أكثر فضولاً وفهمتهم بشكل أفضل.
And although these supposed morons
وبالرغم من أن هؤلاء المغفلون من المفترض
engaged in what appeared to be original thought,
متورطون في ما يظهر انه فكر أصلي،
I said to myself,
قلت لنفسي،
"Um, these guys are highly misinformed,
"امم، هؤلاء الشباب مضللين بدرجة عالية،
at least according to my knowledge."
وفقًا لمعرفتي على الأقل."
Where are these guys getting these arguments from?
من أين يأتي هؤلاء الشباب بحججهم؟
Like, was there some kind of alternative universe
مثل، هل هنالك كون بديل من نوع ما
with alternative facts?
بوقائع بديلة؟
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Was history and gravity optional over there?
هل كانت الجاذبية والتاريخ إختيارية هناك؟
I don't know.
لا أعلم.
But I needed to know. Like, I wanted to know.
ولكنني كنت بحاجة لأعرف. أردت أن أعرف.
And as it turns out, I had no idea about digital echo chambers.
واتضح، بأنني لاأملك أدنى فكرة عن غرف الصدي التقنية.
That same target marketing algorithm
التي تستهدف نفس التسويق
that feeds you more of the products you like to buy
التي تغذيك أكثر بالمنتجات التي تحب شراءها
also feeds you more of the news that you like to hear.
وتغذيك ايضاً بالأخبار التي تود سماعها.
I had been living in an online universe
كنت أعيش في عالم علي الانترنت
that just reflected my worldview back to me.
والذي عكس نظرتي للعالم مرة أخرى
So my timeline was pretty liberal.
فكانت صفحتي الشخصيه فارغه تماما
I had no Breitbart or Infowars or Fox News.
لم يكن لدي بريتبارت اوانفووارس اواخبارفوكس
No, no, I was all MSNBC and The Daily Show,
لا لا كان كله قناه ام اس ان بي سي والديلي شو
CNN and theGrio, right?
سي ان ان وموقع الجريو .اليس كذلك؟
Well, these trolls were hopping the dimensional doorway
حسنا هؤلاء المتصيدون كانوا يتخطون مدخل البعد
and I needed to figure out how.
وكنت بحاجة لمعرفة كيف.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So what I decided to do
لذلك ما قررت القيام به
was trick the Facebook algorithm
هو خداع خوارزمية الفيسبوك
into feeding me more news that I didn't necessarily agree with,
في تغذيتي بالمزيد من الأخبار التي لم أكن أتفق معها بالضرورة ،
and this worked fine for a while, but it wasn't enough,
وهذاعمل جيدا لبعض الوقت، لكنه لم يكن كافياً
because my online footprint
لأن بصماتي على الإنترنت
already established the patterns that I like to hear.
أسست بالفعل الأنماط التي أحب أن أسمعها.
So with the anonymity of the internet,
لذا، مع إخفاء الهوية عبر الإنترنت،
I went undercover.
ذهبت متخفياً.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I set up this ghost profile and went crazy.
قمت بإعداد هذا الملف الشبح وجن جنوني .
Now, on a practical level, it was very simple,
الآن على المستوى العملي كان الامر بسيطا جدا
but on an emotional level, it was kind of daunting,
لكن على المستوى العاطفي، كان نوعا ما شاق
especially with the racist vitriol that I had experienced.
خصوصا مع النقد العنصري اللاذع الذي مررت به
But what I didn't realize is that my trolls were inoculating me,
كن ما لم أكن أدركه هو أن المتصيدون لي كانوا يدخلون في ذهني
thickening my skin,
تثخين بشرتي ،
making me immune to viewpoints that I didn't necessarily agree with,
مما يجعلني في مأمن من وجهات النظر التي _ لا أتفق بالضرورة معها
and so I didn't react to the same things as I would have several months prior.
ولذا لم أتفاعل مع نفس الأشياء كما كان من شأنه أن يكون قبل عدة أشهر.
All right? So I pressed on.
أشهر. حسنا؟ لذلك تقدمت بسرعه .
Noticing that this stuff also worked on YouTube,
مع ملاحظه أن هذه الأشياء عملت أيضا على موقع يوتيوب
I became Lucius25, white supremacist lurker --
أصبحت لوسيوس 25 ، المندسس العنصري الابيض--
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And digitally I began to infiltrate the infamous alt-right movement.
ورقميا بدأت في التسلل لحركة بديل اليمين سيئة السمعة.
Now, my doppelgänger
الآن ، نظيري ( قريني )
was Edgar Rice Burroughs' John Carter character --
كان ادجار رايس بوروز " شخصية جون كارتر --
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
a sci-fi hero who was once a Confederate soldier.
بطل الخيال العلمى الذى كان جندى
And to think, like, years ago, I would have needed acting training
اعتقدت اننى احتاج للتدريب على التمثيل
and, like, makeup and a fake ID.
مثل مكياج او تعريف مزيف
Now I could just lurk.
استطعت فقط التخفى
And so I started
وبدأت
with a little Infowars,
بعدد قليل من المتابعين
went on into some American Renaissance,
لنذهب لعصر النهضة الأمريكية
National Vanguard Alliance,
التحالف الوطنى
and, you know, I started commenting on videos,
وبدأت بالتعليق على الفيدوهات
talking bad about Al Sharpton and Black Lives Matter.
بطريقة سيئة عن الشاربتون وحياة السود
I started bemoaning race baiters like Eric Holder and Barack Obama
لقد بدأت في تحديق عتاة السباق مثل إيريك هولدر وباراك أوباما
and just mirroring the antiblack sentiments
وتحريك بعض المشاعر
that were thrown at me.
التى ألقت على
And to be honest, it was kind of exhilarating.
للأمانة كنت من الاشخاص المنعشين
(Laughter)
ضحك
Like, I would literally spend days clicking through my new racist profile --
وودت ان اقضى ايام فى ملفى الشخصى العنصرى
Goofing off at work in Aryan land. It was something else.
والتخطيط للعمل بالأرض الآرية كان شيئا اخر
(Laughter)
ضحك
And so I then started visiting some of the pages
وبدات بزيارة بعض الصفحات
of my former trolls,
لبعض المتصيدين السابقين
and a lot of these guys were just regular Joes,
وكل معظمهم لديهم وظائف فعلية
a lot of outdoorsmen, hunters, computer nerds,
الكثير من المغامروين والمهوسين بالكمبيوتر
some of them family guys with videos of their families.
وبعض منهم كان يضع فيديوهات له مع عائلته
I mean, for all I know, some of y'all could be in this room right now. Right?
اعنى ان بعضا منهم يمكن ان يكون معنا الان
(Laughter)
ضحك
But when I went undercover, I found a lovely plethora of characters,
ولكن عندما ذهبت متخفيا وجدت بعض من الأشخاص
luminaries like Milo Yiannopoulos, Richard Spencer and David Duke.
نجوم مثل ميلو يانوبولوس ، ريتشارد سبنسر وديفيد ديوك.
All of these guys were thought leaders in their own right,
وكانوا من قادرة الفكر
but over time, the alt-right movement ended up using their information
ولكن مع الوقت انتهى استخدام معلوماتهم
to fuel their momentum.
لملىء نشاطهم
And I'm going to tell you what else led to the momentum of the alt-right:
وساخبرك ايضا ما قادهم الى ذلك
the left wing's wholesale demonization of everything white and male.
الشيطنة في الجناح اليساري من كل شيء أبيض
If you are a pale-skinned penis-haver, you're in league with Satan.
إذا كنت من ذوي البشرة الشاحبة أنت في الدوري مع الشيطان.
(Laughter)
ضحك
Now, would you believe,
الان هل تصدق
would you believe that some people find that offensive?
ان بعض منهم يلقوا هجوما
And --
و..
(Laughter)
ضحك
And so, I mean, listen,
اعنى
I mean, America seems to be hellbent on filling its textbooks
ان امريكا مرحة وهى تملأ كتبها الدراسية
with CliffsNotes versions of its dark past.
من بعض الإصدارات من ماضيها المظلم
This severely, severely decontextualizes race and the anger associated with it,
هذ الشىء غير المبرر والغضب المرتبط بها،
and that is fertile ground for alt-facts to grow.
هو أرض خصبة للحصول على حقائق بديلة للنمو.
Add in the wild landscape of the internet
أضف في المشهد البري للإنترنت
and it's easy to sell rebranded "Mein Kampf" ideas
ومن السهل بيع تلك الأفكار
to a generation who has been failed by public schools.
إلى الجيل الذى فشل بالمدارس
A lot of these ideas, easily debunked.
الكثير، من تلك الأفكار تم فضحها بسهولة
Alt-facts have that quality.
وكل الحقائق اصبحت واضحة
However, one theme kept screaming at me through the subtext of those arguments,
من المواضيع الذى اصبح يصرخ بداخلى
and that was,
وأن كان
why should I be hated for who I cannot help but be?
لماذا يجب ان اكره من لا يقدم المساعدة
Now, as a black man in America, that resonated with me.
الان كرجل اسود فى امريكا فهذا اعطى صدى لى
I have spent so much time
استغرقت الكثير من الوقت
defending myself against attempts to demonize me
لاجد تعريفا لنفسى بدلا من تشويهها
and make me apologize for who I am,
وجعل نفسى يعتذر لمن هو فى الحقيقة
trying to portray me as something that I'm not,
واحاول تصويرى كشىء لم يكن
some kind of thug or gangster, a menace to society.
نوع من البلطجة أو العصابات، خطر على المجتمع.
Unexpected compassion.
وتعاطف غير متوقع
Wow.
مدهش
Now, listen,
الان انصتوا
the historical source of the demonization of black males and white males
المصدر التاريخي للشيطنة من الذكور السود و الذكور البيض
is highly different,
مختلفا تماما
and where you fall on this argument,
وعندما تقع فى خلاف
sadly, tends to be an accident of birth.
للأسف ، يميل إلى أن يكون حادث ولادة.
Now, you're probably surprised by this perspective,
الآن ، أنت على الأرجح متفاجئ بهذا المنظور،
and so was I.
وانا كذلك
Never in a billion years did I think that I could have some kind of compassion
لم أفكر أبداً أن يكون هناك نوع من الشفقة
for people who hated my guts.
للأشخاص الذين يكرهون شجاعتى
Now, mind you, not enough compassion like I want to be friends.
وضع فى الاعتبار انك تريد تكون اصدقاء
I don't have infinite olive branches to extend to people
ليس لديّ أغصان زيتون لانهائية لتمتد إلى الناس
who, like, would not want to see me on this planet. Right?
الذين لا يريدون رؤيتى على هذا الكوكب
But just enough compassion to understand how they got to where they are.
لكن ما يكفي من الرأفة لفهم كيف وصلوا إلى حيث هم.
And to be honest,
وكونك امين
there were a couple of fair points.
فانت تلك نقاط عادلة
One of them was how liberals have this wide acceptance for everybody
واحد منهم كان كيف الليبراليين أن ينالوا لدينا هذا القبول الواسع للجميع
except for those with honestly held conservative viewpoints.
باستثناء أولئك الذين يمتلكون بصدق وجهات النظر المحافظة.
(Laughter)
ضحك
Heaven forbid you love God, this country and mean it. Right?
ويحبون الله وهذه البلد بحق
And another thing that they talked about was this fear that they had
وشيء آخر تحدثوا عنه كان هذا الخوف الذي لديهم صحيح ؟
of something that they labeled as "white genocide,"
من شيء وصفوه باسم "الابادة الجماعية البيضاء"
that diversity would be a force that would wipe them out.
هذا التنوع سيكون قوة من شأنه أن يمحوهم.
Now listen, I know what it is to fear
اعرف ماهو هذا الخوف
for the fate of your people.
لمصير شعبك
Between crack, AIDS, gang violence,
بين المخدرات، الإيدز، عنف العصابات،
mass incarceration, gentrification, police shootings,
السجن الجماعي، التجديد، وإطلاق النار من قبل الشرطة،
black people have more than enough reasons to stay up at night.
الناس السود لديهم المزيد من الأسباب الكافية للبقاء في الليل.
But if nature is into diversity and you are not,
ولكن إذا كانت الطبيعة تتنوع وأنت لا،
you're going to lose that fight, buddy.
ستفقد تلك المعركة يا صديقي.
(Laughter)
ضحك
(Applause)
تصفيق
You see, nature doesn't care about your race. That's man-made.
ترى، الطبيعة لا تهتم عن عرقك هذا من صنع الإنسان.
Nature just cares about healthy organisms,
الطبيعة تهتم فقط بالكائنات الحية الصحية،
and your precious ethnic features are expendable to that aim.
وميزاتك العرقية الثمينة قابلة للاستهلاك لهذا الهدف.
So the moment that you let go of that racist identity
لذا ، لحظة تركك تلك الهوية العنصرية
and relatch onto humanity,
و عادوا الى الإنسانية،
all your problems go away.
وستذهب كل مشاكلك
(Applause)
تصفيق
I'm going to tell you what race ain't about to die out:
سوف أخبرك ما السباق الذى ليس على وشك الموت:
the human race.
هو سباق الإنسانية
Join the party. The water's great.
انضم للحفل الماء رائع
Until the water gets too hot, but that's another TED Talk.
حتى يصبح الماء حارا جدا
(Laughter)
ضحك
The point is that to get to this point of understanding,
المستهدف هو جعل تلك النقطة تفهم
you have to let go of that fear
يجيب ان تدهب خوفك
and embrace your curiosity,
واختبر شجاعتك
and sadly, too many people will not take that journey
لذلك العديد من الناس لن تغامر وتبدا الرحلة
to see the world from the other side.
لرؤية العالم من الجانب الآخر
And, I mean, let's be honest,
اعنى ان تكون امينا
that doesn't just go for progressives,
ولا تكون فقط في اتجاه ما هو متقدم
but also to the right wing and conservatives.
ولكن أيضا إلى الجناح الأيمن والمحافظون.
You know, as fair as some of their points were,
كما تعلمون، عادلة كما كانت بعض نقاطهم،
they were still trapped in their own echo chambers,
كانوا لا يزالون محاصرين في غرف الصدى الخاصة بهم،
recycling old, outdated points of view,
إعادة لوجهات نظر قديمة عفا عنها الزمن
never getting a diversity in perspective,
أبدا الحصول على التنوع في المنظور،
not making them well-rounded in their worldview.
لا تجعلها مستديرة في نظرتهم للعالم.
So they're not hearing certain anti-racist and political voices,
لذا فهم لا يسمعون بعض الأصوات المناهضة للعنصرية والسياسية
voices like Tim Wise
أصوات مثل تيم وايز
and Michelle Alexander, Dr. Joy DeGruy, Boyce Watkins, Tariq Nasheed.
وميشيل ألكسندر، د. جوي ديجروي ، بويس واتكينز ، طارق نشيد.
All of these voices have the answers to the questions that they want,
كل هذه الأصوات لديها إجابات على الأسئلة التي يريدونها،
but unfortunately they will not hear them due to the power of these echo chambers.
لكن لسوء الحظ لن يسمعوهم بسبب قوة هذه الغرف
We have got to break out of these digital divides,
يجب أن نخرج من هذه الفجوات الرقمية،
because as our technology advances,
لأنه مع تقدم التكنولوجيا لدينا،
the consequences of our tribalism become more dangerous.
عواقب القبلية لدينا تصبح أكثر خطورة.
And this whole experience taught me something:
وهذه التجربة بأكملها علمتني شيء ما:
our gadgets ain't going to save us.
أدواتنا لن تنقذنا.
All these technological devices
كل هذه الأجهزة التكنولوجية
are only mastery of the universe out there, not the one in here.
هي فقط التمكن من العالم هناك ، وليس هنا.
And so that's all IQ, not EQ.
هذا كل شىء كافى
That's a dangerous imbalance.
هذا اختلال خطير.
Where do you get the emotional intelligence,
من اين تحصل الذكاء العاطفي
the character development,
وتطور الشخصيات
the virtues of patience, forbearance, compassion,
فضائل الصبر، والرحمة،
you know, the things that make sure that these devices, however advanced,
كما تعلمون، الأشياء التي تتأكد أن هذه الأجهزة، ومع ذلك المتقدمة،
become a blessing and not a curse?
تصبح نعمة وليست نقمة؟
Seems to be me that humanity itself needs an upgrade.
يبدو لي أن الإنسانية نفسها يحتاج إلى ترقية.
Now --
الان
(Applause)
تصفيق
That's a big task, understandably,
هذه مهمة كبيرة، من المفهوم،
but I don't believe in any kind of unbeatable monster.
لكنني لا أصدق اى نوع من الوحش الذي لا يهزم
There was no giant out there without perhaps a simple Achilles heel.
ربما لم يكن هناك عملاق هناك دون كعب أخيل بسيط.
And what if I told you
وماذا لو قلت لك
that one of the best ways to actually overcome this
ان هذا واحد من أفضل الطرق للتغلب على هذا الواقع
is to have courageous conversations
هو إجراء محادثات شجاعة
with difficult people,
مع اشخاص مختلفون
people who do not see the world the same way that you see the world?
الناس الذين لا يرون العالم بنفس الطريقة التي ترى العالم بها؟
Oh yes, folks, conversations may be indeed the key to that upgrade,
أوه نعم ، الناس، قد تكون المحادثات في الواقع المفتاح لهذه الترقية،
because remember,
لان للتذكر
language was the first form of virtual reality.
كانت اللغة هي الشكل الأول من الواقع الافتراضي.
It is literally a symbolic representation of the physical world,
إنه حرفياً تمثيل رمزي للعالم المادي،
and through this device, we change the physical world.
ومن خلال هذا الجهاز، نغير العالم المادي.
Keep in mind, conversations stop violence,
تذكر أن المحادثات تتوقف عن العنف،
conversations start countries,
المحادثات تبنى الدول،
they build bridges,
والجسور
and when the chips are down,
وعندما تنخفض النقاش،
conversations are the last tools that humans use
المحادثات هي الأدوات الأخيرة التى يستخدمها البشر
before they pick up their guns.
قبل أن يلتقطوا أسلحتهم.
And I ain't talking about online safe conversations
وأنا لا أتحدث حول المحادثات الآمنة عبر الإنترنت
from the security of your laptop.
من الكمبيوتر المحمول الخاص بك.
No.
لا
I'm talking about in-your-face conversations with real, breathing people.
أنا أتحدث وجه لوجه مع أشخاص حقيقيين فيهم الروح.
And for me, this looks like running a community forum
وبالنسبة لي ، هذا يبدو مثل تشغيل منتدى المجتمع
called Shop Talk Live.
تسمى شوي توك لايف
Now, in Shop Talk Live -- somebody's been there, right?
وفيها يوجد شخص هنا أليس كذلك ؟
In Shop Talk Live,
فى شوبتوك لايف
we have the conversations that change lives.
لدينا المحادثات هذا التغيير يعيش.
We meet the community right where they are,
نلتقي بالمجتمع الحق أين هم ،
and we've done everything from divert gang violence in real time
وقمنا بكل شيء من تحويل عنف العصابات في الوقت الحقيقي
to help find people jobs
ومساعدة الناس للحصول على وظائف
to mentoring homeless youth.
لتوجيه الشباب اللذين بلا مأوى.
And the reason why we needed to do this
والسبب في أننا بحاجة إلى القيام بذلك
is because there was a severe lack of trust in the black community
لأنه كان هناك نقص حاد للثقة في مجتمع السود
due to the violence of the crack era.
بسبب عنف عصر الكراك
And so we ended up taking agency into our own hands,
وهكذا انتهى الأمر الوكالة في أيدينا،
solving our own problems,
وحل جميع مشاكلنا
not waiting for anybody else.
لا تنتظر أي شخص آخر
And the truth is,
والحقيقة هى
from the mayor to the felon,
من رئيس البلدية إلى المجرم،
you're going to find them in that barber shop.
سوف تجدهم في محل الحلاقة هذا.
And so what we did was just organize what was already going on.
و ما فعلناه هو فقط تنظيم ما كان يحدث بالفعل.
And so what I started doing was mining these alternative viewpoints
وهذا ما بدأت به كانت تعدين هذه وجهات النظر البديلة
from these alternative digital universes,
من هذه الأكوان الرقمية البديلة،
dissecting them, breaking them down into controversial talking points.
تشريحهم، وكسرهم في نقاط الحديث المثيرة للجدل.
Then, with my cell phone,
ثم، مع هاتفي الخلوي،
I flipped the internet against itself
لقد انقلبت الإنترنت ضد نفسه
and began to broadcast these live conversations
وبدأت في البث هذه المحادثات الحية
to my online followers.
لمتابعى
This made them want to leave the safety of their laptops
هذا يجعلهم يريدون رحيل عن أجهزة المحمول
and meet us in person to have real conversations
وتلبية لنا شخصيا لإجراء محادثات حقيقية
with real people in real life.
مع اشخاص حقيقيين فى الحياة
And we did this. Thank you.
ونحن نفعل ذلك .شكرا لكم
(Applause)
تصفيق
Sometimes I sit back, and I reflect on the paradox
أحيانا أجلس، وأفكر في المفارقة
of me just trying to solve the problems,
لحل المشاكل،
us trying to solve the problems in our own communities --
نحن نحاول حل المشاكل في مجتمعاتنا -
we build bridges to so many other communities,
نبني الجسور إلى العديد من المجتمعات الأخرى،
from the LGBTQ community to the Arab immigrant community
من مجتمع المهاجرين العرب
and even sat down with somebody with a Confederate flag on their hat
وحتى الجلسوس مع شخص ما من الكونفدرالية
and talked about the things that actually matter.
وتحدث عن الأشياء في الواقع
It is time that we stop trying
انها الوقت للتوقف عن الكتابة
to hack our way around the human experience.
لاختراق طريقنا حول التجربة البشرية.
There is no way out of each other.
لا توجد طريقة للخروج من بعضها البعض.
Stop trying to find one.
توقف عن الكتابة لايجاد شخص
(Applause)
تصفيق
We have to understand something.
علينا أن نفهم شيئا.
Human beings all want the same things
كل البشر يريدون نفس الأشياء
and we have to go through each other to get these things.
وعلينا أن نمر بعضنا البعض للحصول على هذه الأشياء.
These courageous conversations are the way that these bridges are built.
هذه المحادثات الشجاعة هي الطريقة التي يتم بناء هذه الجسور.
It's time that we start seeing people as people
لقد حان الوقت أن نبدأ رؤية الناس كأشخاص
and not simply the ideas that we project onto them or react to.
وليس مجرد الأفكار التي نعرضها عليهم أو نتفاعل معها.
Human beings are not the barriers
البشر ليسوا الحواجز
but the gateways to the very things that we want.
لكن البدايات إلى الأشياء التي نريدها.
This is a collective and conscious evolution.
هذا تطور جمعي وواع.
My journey began with a terribly popular cell phone video
بدأت رحلتي مع شعبية الهاتف الخليوي رهيبة
and a fallen friend.
وصديق
Your journey begins right about now.
تبدأ رحلتك الآن.
Join the renaissance in human connection.
الانضمام إلى النهضة في اتصال الإنسان.
It is going to happen with or without you.
سوف يحدث معك أو بدونك.
My suggestion: pick a topic, and start a community dialogue
اقتراحي: اختيار موضوعً وبدء حوار مجتمعي
in your neck of the woods.
في عنق الغابة.
Meet folks back in real life.
بجتمع الناس مرة واحدة فى الحياة
And I'm going to tell you,
سوف احدثك
when you trick the algorithm of your existence,
عندما تخدع الخوارزمية من وجودك،
you will get some diversified experiences.
ستحصل على بعض الخبرات المتنوعة
It is time to grow, people.
حان الوقت لتنمو الناس
And when we do this, not if,
وعندما نفعل هذا ، ماذا لو
it will be clear that the key to this upgrade
سيكون واضحا هذا المفتاح لهذه الترقية
was always our inner world, not some device that we create,
كان دائما عالمنا الداخلي ، ليس بعض الأجهزة التي نخلقها ،
and will forever be, each other.
وسوف نكون إلى الأبد ، بعضنا البعض.
Thank you.
شكرا لكم
(Applause)
تصفيق